{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "sourceDate": 1585810800.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1585810800.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586037437.715155, "questionText": "How concerned should I be about COVID‑19 ?", "answerText": "On March 11 , 2020 , the World Health Organization ( WHO ) declared that the new coronavirus , SARS‑CoV‑2 and the disease it causes , COVID‑19 , is a global pandemic because of how fast it is spreading across the globe . A pandemic means a disease that is prevalent and spreading over the whole world . According to the WHO , this is the first pandemic caused by a coronavirus . The good news for the U.S. is that if we all change our behavior starting today , we can work together to help slow the spread of the virus . Slowing the spread helps hospitals and healthcare workers keep up with the healthcare needs of the community without becoming overwhelmed .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "40427c70-76bf-11ea-b578-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "404388b8-76bf-11ea-8af4-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "4043898a-76bf-11ea-be24-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "sourceDate": 1585810800.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1585810800.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586037438.502203, "questionText": "How do I protect myself and others from COVID‑19 ?", "answerText": "Coronaviruses are most commonly spread through coughing and sneezing , personal contact like shaking hands , and touching a surface with the virus and then touching your eyes , nose or mouth . Slowing down the spread beginning today will help protect you and everyone else . The virus is especially hard on our most vulnerable populations , such as seniors and those with chronic medical conditions . These are simple steps everyone can take to help prevent spreading COVID‑19 and other viruses . Make them a habit now and teach these habits to those around you . \n Wash your hands often with soap and water for at least 20 seconds , especially after going to the bathroom . Also wash them before eating and after blowing your nose , coughing or sneezing . If there 's no soap and water , use an alcohol - based hand sanitizer with at least 60 % alcohol . \n Do n't touch your eyes , nose and mouth with unwashed hands . \n Avoid close contact with people who are sick . \n Stay home when you are sick . \n Cover your cough or sneeze with a tissue , then throw the tissue in the trash and wash your hands afterward . \n Disinfect surfaces , buttons , handles , knobs and other places touched often .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "40ba9476-76bf-11ea-bb13-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "40ba9566-76bf-11ea-84ed-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "40ba95ac-76bf-11ea-b60b-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "sourceDate": 1585810800.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1585810800.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586037439.258973, "questionText": "Is the risk for getting COVID‑19 the same for everyone ?", "answerText": "No , but as the virus spreads , it affects multiple age groups . People in high - risk groups for getting very sick from COVID‑19 include people 65 years and older and those with chronic medical conditions , such as heart disease , lung disease , diabetes , and cancer . Those who have a compromised immune system are also at higher risk than those in the general population . If you are in one of the higher - risk groups mentioned above and you develop fever or symptoms , call your doctor . If you are not sick enough to be hospitalized , you can recover at home .   ▲ Top", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "412e0dd4-76bf-11ea-b7c1-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "412e0eb0-76bf-11ea-9b94-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "412e0ef6-76bf-11ea-8a55-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "sourceDate": 1585810800.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1585810800.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586037440.0138218, "questionText": "What is social distancing , and should I do it ?", "answerText": "Social distancing involves staying away from other people to avoid catching or spreading a virus . It 's a fancy term for avoiding crowds and minimizing physical contact . This could mean avoiding concerts or weddings , skipping the handshake , and/or staying six feet from others . Health professionals believe COVID‑19 spreads from person to person by droplets from coughing and sneezing . The safest thing to do during an outbreak is stay home as much as possible and minimize close contact with others . ▲ Top", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "41a13c14-76bf-11ea-86f8-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "41a13d06-76bf-11ea-b84b-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "41a13d54-76bf-11ea-aa97-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "sourceDate": 1585810800.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1585810800.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586037440.794513, "questionText": "Should I , or my family , go to large - scale events , sporting events , conferences and concerts ? How do I make that decision ?", "answerText": "We all want to go about our daily lives as normally as possible . But organizations are canceling and rescheduling events like conferences , rodeos and festivals . If you are considering attending a large gathering , consider your personal risk of getting and spreading the virus . If you are age 65 or older , or have a chronic medical condition , you need to be very thoughtful about your risk . Then decide for yourself whether you want to attend .   ▲ Top", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "42185bd2-76bf-11ea-a76e-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "42185cae-76bf-11ea-a23e-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "42185cfe-76bf-11ea-9e37-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "sourceDate": 1585810800.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1585810800.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586037441.606503, "questionText": "How long does the COVID‑19 virus live on surfaces ?", "answerText": "We do n't know yet . But we do know that if you clean and disinfect surfaces often , you can get rid of the virus . Think about surfaces that you and others touch often . Those may include elevator buttons , lockers , remote controls , light switches , stair rails , door knobs , drawer pulls and appliance handles . Clean them multiple times daily . The Environmental Protection Agency ( EPA ) published a list of products to use against coronavirus . Refer to it to learn about cleaning products that help slow the spread of the virus . Be sure to check manufacturer 's guidelines about cleaning electronic equipment , such as cell phones , laptops , touch screens and keyboards .   ▲ Top", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "42944238-76bf-11ea-82f6-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "42944334-76bf-11ea-aa2b-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "429444fe-76bf-11ea-97ac-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "sourceDate": 1585810800.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1585810800.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586037442.401199, "questionText": "Do home remedies work against COVID‑19 ?", "answerText": "Home remedies and therapies are not proven to help alleviate symptoms nor ensure you wo n't get it . That 's why it is important to focus on prevention : always practice good hygiene and stay away from sick people . Eating healthy , regular physical exercise , good sleep and lowering stress levels are great ways to keep your immune system healthy .   ▲ Top", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "430d8508-76bf-11ea-8a3e-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "430d85f8-76bf-11ea-919d-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "430d863e-76bf-11ea-aaa9-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "sourceDate": 1585810800.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1585810800.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586037443.214377, "questionText": "What about my pets , are they at risk for COVID‑19 ? What about livestock ?", "answerText": "Currently there is no known risk that pets or livestock can get sick from COVID‑19 . However , animals do spread disease so always wash your hands after being around them . If you are sick , limit contact with animals to minimize risk to them .   ▲ Top", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "438999c2-76bf-11ea-9de0-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "43899a80-76bf-11ea-88ae-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "43899ac6-76bf-11ea-a13f-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "sourceDate": 1585810800.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1585810800.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586037444.030606, "questionText": "Stores are running out of supplies — what do I really need and for how long ?", "answerText": "While we want to be prepared , we do n't want to strain our suppliers and hoard things our neighbors need . Protecting them protects you . Make sure you have several weeks ' worth of medications and supplies like frozen foods and canned goods for people and animals in your care in case you need to stay home .   ▲ Top", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "440625a8-76bf-11ea-8a92-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "4406267a-76bf-11ea-8217-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "440626c2-76bf-11ea-a9a6-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "sourceDate": 1585810800.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1585810800.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586037444.839961, "questionText": "I feel sick . Do I need to get tested if I think I have COVID‑19 ?", "answerText": "Your doctor will help make the decision whether you need to get tested , based on your symptoms and risk category . Symptoms of COVID‑19 may show up 2–14 days after exposure and may include fever , cough and shortness of breath . If you are age 65 or older and/or have other medical problems like heart disease , lung disease , diabetes , or cancer — and have fever or symptoms — call your doctor . If you are not sick enough to be hospitalized , you can recover at home . If you are in generally good health and you get sick , stay home and take care of yourself like you would for the flu . If your symptoms worsen , call your doctor .   ▲ Top", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "4481a52c-76bf-11ea-b113-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "4481a608-76bf-11ea-a49b-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "4481a64c-76bf-11ea-8af2-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": ""}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "sourceDate": 1585810800.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1585810800.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586037445.615485, "questionText": "What is the treatment for COVID ?", "answerText": "There is no cure for COVID‑19 yet . There is also no vaccine available yet , either . The best we can do is treat symptoms . Only the very sick will need hospitalization .   ▲ Top", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "44f7fb0a-76bf-11ea-b040-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "44f7fbdc-76bf-11ea-bba8-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "44f7fc22-76bf-11ea-b764-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": ""}
